I said the 20-somethings are dumb. They're not dumb.
我说过二十多岁的人很蠢。 他们并不蠢。
It's just certain ways of the world.
只是他们对这个世界的某些理解方式不同。
The reason I say that, you watch, in the not too distant future, hackers are going to knock out our cellphones and the internet.
我这么说的原因是，你看，在不久的将来，黑客会让我们的手机和互联网瘫痪。
These 20-somethings will come to a stop, stare at their phone, and have no idea what to do next.
这些二十多岁的人会停在那里，盯着手机，不知道下一步该怎么办。
Because they've always had an internet connection.
因为他们一直都有互联网连接。
If we lose the internet, us old folks, we got a plan B.
如果互联网消失，我们这些老家伙还有备用方案。
You 20-somethings are going to have to find a bunch of old people and ask us how to do stuff.
你们这些二十多岁的人将不得不找一群老人，问我们事情该怎么做。
"Hey, mister, can you help me get home? "
嘿，先生，你能帮我回家吗？"
I don't know how to do directions."
我不知道怎么导航。
Well, I can draw you a map but you're gonna have to listen and store the information in your head.
嗯，我可以给你画一张地图，但你得听清楚，并把信息记在脑子里。
And I'm not here to tell you life was better before cellphones. It wasn't.I love my phone.
我并不是来告诉你手机出现以前的生活更好的。 事实并不是这样。我喜欢我的手机。
I'm addicted to that thing.
我对那个东西上瘾了。
You ever lose your phone?
你有没有丢过手机？
Oh, that's a panic attack.
哦，那简直就是恐慌发作。
I lost my kid at the mall one time and didn't panic like that.
有一次我在商场弄丢了孩子，但我都没有那么慌。
Because I have two kids.
因为我有两个孩子。
Never has technology moved so quickly as the past 20-plus years.
过去二十多年里，科技的发展速度从未如此之快。
My son was at my house a couple of years ago.
几年前，我儿子在我家。
He called my mom, his grandma.
他给我的妈妈，也就是他的奶奶，打了电话。
He turns to me, he goes, "I think grandma's phone broken."
他转向我，说："我觉得奶奶的手机坏了。"
I go, why?
我说："为什么？"
He goes, "listen to this."
他说："听这个。"
It's a busy signal.
这是忙音。
He'd never heard one.
他以前从没听过这种声音。
He goes, "now what do I do?"
他说："那我现在怎么办？"
Hang up.
挂掉电话。
He goes, "how do I leave a message?"
他说："我要怎么留言？"
You don't.
不用。
He goes, "now what do I do?"
他说："那现在怎么办？"
I go, wait a few minutes. Call her back.
我说："等几分钟，再给她打回去。"
He goes, "that's stupid."
他说："那太蠢了。"
And I don't know what it was like in your house growing up.
我不知道你们小时候家里的情况是什么样的。
My house growing up, my dad never answered the phone.
我小时候家里，我爸爸从来不接电话。
He wasn't getting out of his big old chair.
他才不会从他那把又大又旧的椅子上起来。
That phone rang, he just looked at us kids.
电话一响，他只是看着我们这些孩子。
It was our job to answer the phone, right?
接电话是我们的任务，对吧？
I was telling my son that story one day, he goes, "why didn't you tell your dad to get the phone?"
有一天我给儿子讲这个故事，他说："你为什么不让你爸爸去接电话？"
My World War II marine dad?
我那个参加过二战的海军陆战队老爸？
I tried it once.
我试过一次。
Had no idea he could get out of the chair that quickly.
完全没想到他能那么快从椅子上站起来。
When I woke up, that phone was inside me.
当我醒来的时候，那部电话已经插进我身体里了。
Here's something that kills me about technology and old people.
关于科技和老年人，有一件事真的让我觉得特别好笑。
By old people, I'm talking about people my age.
我说的老年人，其实指的是和我同年龄的人。
Watch us when people are taking pictures.
看看别人拍照时我们这些人的反应。
They've got the camera. We all stop.
他们拿着相机。我们都会停下来。
We don't walk in front of it because we think we're going to ruin the film.
我们不会走到镜头前，因为我们以为会毁掉胶卷。
Hey, Boomer, no more film.
嘿，婴儿潮一代，现在已经没有胶卷了。
Keep moving.
继续走，不要停。
These guys delete more pictures in an hour than we used to take in a year.
这些人一小时删除的照片，比我们过去一年拍的还多。
You remember roll of 24?
你还记得 24 张装的胶卷吗？
That thing would last year all year.
那东西一年都用不完。
You get that back, you go, look, there's Uncle Billy.
你拿回来照片时，会说："看，这是 Billy 叔叔。"
He's been dead at least a year.
他至少已经去世一年了。
Oh my. I got some new Uncle Billy photos.
天啊，我有一些新的 Billy 叔叔照片。
And photos weren't unlimited, you had to keep track.
照片不是无限的，你必须控制数量。
Remember that little counter on the bottom of the camera told you how many were left?
还记得相机底部那个小计数器告诉你还剩多少张照片吗？
That's why all the sasquatch photos are crappy.
这就是为什么所有大脚怪照片都那么糟糕。
Everybody was down to their last shot.
每个人都只剩最后一次拍摄机会。
Like, oh, there is. Click. Ah.
比如："哦，它在那里。"咔嚓。啊。
Behind a tree.
（结果照片里）在一棵树后面。
Before COVID, I worked in Singapore and Hong Kong.
新冠疫情之前，我在新加坡和香港工作。
I worked these English speaking comedy clubs and I flew from Hong Kong to Singapore on Tigair.
我在这些英语喜剧俱乐部工作，然后乘坐 Tigair 从香港飞到新加坡。
It's this cut rate Asian airline, they cramming you in close together.
这是一家廉价亚洲航空公司，他们把乘客挤得非常紧。
And I don't feel like a big man.
我平时并不觉得自己是个大块头。
But in Asia, I'm gigantic.
但在亚洲，我简直算巨大型的人。
I did not realize it till I was standing at the gate looking around going, oh my, I'm the biggest guy here by a lot.
直到我站在登机口环顾四周，我才意识到："天啊，我明显是这里最大的人。"
So I'm 6'1", 190. 195. 200. Probably 202 this morning.
所以我身高 6 英尺 1 英寸，体重 190 磅。195。200。今天早上可能 202 磅。
Anyway, I was the biggest guy by a lot on the jet and I had a window seat.
总之，在飞机上我明显是体型最大的人，而且我坐的是靠窗的位置。
There was a guy in the aisle and I said, can I sneak past you?
过道那里坐着一个人，我问："我可以从你旁边挤过去吗？"
He said, "your sneaking days are over, my friend."
他说："你的偷偷挤过去的日子结束了，朋友。"